Preliminary Guide to the Rufus Lusk & Sons business and personal records, 1896-1994 MS2189
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Civic and personal records, 1896-1971; Series 2
  - Washington Taxpayers' Association (WTA) and Washington Taxpayers' Protective Association (WTPA), 1933-1959; Series 2 Subseries 2
    - District unemployment compensation board, 1940; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - District unemployment compensation board, 1935-1939; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - E [WTA], 1948; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Executive Committee [WTPA], 1948; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Executive Committee [WTPA], 1950; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - F [WTA], 1941-1948; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 9)
    - Financial statements [WTA], 1949; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 10)
    - Financial statements [WTA], 1950; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 11)
    - G [WTA], 1941-1948; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 12)
    - Gas Tax Fund, D.C. [WTA], 1946; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 13)
    - Government departments and agencies [WTA], undated; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 14)
    - Government Research Association [WTA], 1948-1949; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 15)
    - H [WTA], 1939-1950; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 16)
    - Highway department [WTA], 1929-1936; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 17)
    - I [WTA], 1946-1949; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 18)
    - Income tax information [WTA], 1945; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 19)
    - Income tax, D.C. [WTA], 1939-1940; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 20)
    - Income tax returns [WTA], 1942-1958; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 21)
    - J [WTA], 1940-1948; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 22)
    - Judicial criminal statistics [WTA], 1940-1941; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 23)
    - K [WTA], 1942-1946; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 24)
    - L [WTA], 1941-1948; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 25)
    - Letters to and from contributors [WTA], 1949; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 26)
    - Letters to and from contributors [WTA], 1950; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 27)
    - Lobby act registrations [WTA], 1948-1950; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 28)
    - Lobby act registrations [WTA], 1950; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 84, Folder 29)
    - Mc [WTA], 1947; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - McCarran D.C. vote bill [WTA], 1943; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - M [WTA], 1941-1950; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Membership campaign [WTA], 1949; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Mimeographed bulletins [WTA], 1949; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Mimeographed bulletins [WTA], 1950; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Motor vehicle parking agency [WTA], 1946; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - N [WTA], 1940-1948; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - National Association of Home Builders [WTA], 1946; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - News releases [WTA], 1949; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - News releases [WTA], 1950-1955; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - O [WTA], 1940-1947; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 12)
    - P [WTA], 1940-1948; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 13)
    - Planning committee (Board of Commissioners, D.C.) [WTA], 1946-1947; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 14)
    - [Police] [WTA], 1950; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 15)
    - Police department, D.C. [WTA], 1948; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 16)
    - Policemen and firemen pay increases [WTA], 1941; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 17)
    - Policemen and firement pensions [WTA], 1935-1949; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 18)
    - Postwar planning, Washington, D.C., 1941-1944; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 19)
    - Public assistance division relief figures [WTA], 1935-1939; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 20)
    - Public assistance division relief figures [WTA], 1940-1942; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 21)
    - Public housing [WTA], 1946; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 22)
    - Public Welfare, Board of, 1944-1946; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 85, Folder 23)
    - R [WTA], 1942-1948; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Receipts [WTPA], 1948-1949; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Receipts [WTPA], 1950; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Real estate assessments, D.C. [WTA], 1937; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Relief [WTA], 1936-1940; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Rent control [WTA], 1946-1949; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Rodlun, Troy [WTA], 1948-1949; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - S [WTA], 1940-1943; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - Sales tax, D.C. [WTA], 1949; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - School costs [WTA], 1937-1946; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Subway, proposed D.C. [WTA], 1945; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - T [WTA], 1940-1946; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 12)
    - Taxpayers' Associations bulletins and miscellaneous information [WTA], 1947-1949; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 13)
    - Tax sale, D.C. [WTA], 1936-1944; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 14)
    - U [WTA], 1944-1950; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 15)
    - V [WTA], 1941-1944; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 16)
    - Votes for Washington [WTA], 1947-1949; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 17)
    - W [WTA], 1940-1947; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 18)
    - [WTA], 1943-1961; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 86, Folder 19)
    - Washington Taxpayers Association Dinner, 1951-1959; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 97, Folder 13)
    - Washington Taxpayers Association, 1955 March 24; Series 2 Subseries2 (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - Personal papers, 1896-1966; Series 2 Subseries 3
    For ease of browsing the files related to personal papers for the Lusk family have been intellectually grouped together in this subseries. The files in this subseries are arranged in original order by box number.
    - An American Taxpayer looks at Europe by Rufus S. Lusk Sr. vols. I-X, 1955-1964; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence European trip, 1965; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence to office rufus lusk European trip, 1959; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 63, Folder 15)
    - An American Taxpayer looks at Europe newsletter, 1955-1959; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - An American Taxpayer looks at Europe newsletter, 1960-1965; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - An American Taxpayer looks at Europe newsletter original drawings, undated; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Scotland Yard correspondence, 1961-1962; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Lusk, Rufus S. 1717 37th St., 1948-1949; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Answers to American taxpayers letters, 1965-1966; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - The Army and Navy Club, 1961; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - West Coast correspondence R.S.L., 1965; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - West Coat trip expenses, 1965; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, RSL, Sr., 1965; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Postcards and snapshots, undated; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 74, Folder 16)
    - Itinerary Cunard programs [1/2], 1955; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 74, Folder 17)
    - Itinerary Cunard programs [2/2], 1955; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Bulletins and newspapers, 1955; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1957-1959; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1957; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Names - addresses - notes, undated; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Hotel bills, 1955; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Co-op, Circa 1954; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Germany - general, Circa 1955; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - British Isles - general, 1955; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - USA correspondence - Re Europe, 1955; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Letters received while in Europe, 1955; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - American Taxpayer looks at Europe, 1956; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with office, 1956; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Receipts, letters, name cards, 1896-1955; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 97, Folder 11)
    - Lambda Alpha GW Chapter, 1983; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 97, Folder 12)
    - 1824 Jefferson Place, 1955; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 97, Folder 14)
    - Material used in exhibit for opening of Lusk Collection, undated; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 98)
      This title describes the entire box.
    - A selection of cases on agency by James B. Flynn, 1933; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 109, Folder 4)
    - personal materials, undated; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - certificate appointing Rufus S. Lusk Sr. to Citizens Zoning Advisory Committee, 1960; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - certificate appointing Rufus S. Lusk Sr. to Citizens Zoning Advisory Committee, 1961; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - Photographs, 1920-1948; Series 2 Subseries 3 (Box 111, Folder 4)
      The folder contains three rolled images that may require preservation. First image: Rep State Com. Pinner November 1940 Hotel Willard. Second image: Le Diner Des Amis D'escoffier Statler Hotel May 6, 1948. Third image: First Pep Dinner of the Spring Thrift Drive National Thrift Bond Corporation May 1, 1920
- Transportation, 1937-1988; Series 3
  The files in this series are arranged in box number order to leave some understanding of how these records were originally grouped together.
  Scope and Contents
  The material in this series include correspondence, reports, memorandum, and photographs. These materials relate to the Tri-State Commission and Metro. These materials are from Jerome M. Alper. An attorney and author of History of the Negotiations of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority.
  - Tri-State - Consent Legislation correspondence, 1966; Series 3 (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Tri-State - Consent Legislation House Hearings, 1966; Series 3 (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Tri-State Consent Legislation (JMA) House Debate, undated; Series 3 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Tri-State Consent Legislation Legislation, 1966; Series 3 (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Tri-State Consent Legislation Memoranda, 1966; Series 3 (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Tri-State Consent Legislation Press Releases, 1966; Series 3 (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Tri-State Consent Legislation Supporting Material, undated; Series 3 (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Tri-State Consent Legislation Testimony - House Hearings, 1966; Series 3 (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - Tri-State Consent Legislation Work Papers, 1937-1966; Series 3 (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - Tri-State Commission - NVTD Current, 1964-1965; Series 3 (Box 95, Folder 10)
  - Tri-State Commission - Proprietary Compact (Agenda of Meetings) and notice to members of Commission, 1962-1966; Series 3 (Box 95, Folder 11)
  - Tri-State Commission Transportation Planning Board [1/2], 1965; Series 3 (Box 95, Folder 12)
  - Tri-State Commission Transportation Planning Board [2/2], 1965 April; Series 3 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Tri-State - Washington Suburban Transit District - Work Papers, 1965; Series 3 (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - NCTA Transportation Plan [1/2], 1963-1965; Series 3 (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - NCTA Transportation Plan [2/2], 1962-1965; Series 3 (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Tri-State Commission (Comments on NCTA 1964-1965 Proposals), 1960-1965; Series 3 (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Tri-State comments on NCTA 1963 Proposals (S. 1647, H.R. 6633 and 7249 and H.R. 8929), 1963-1966; Series 3 (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Northern Virginia Transp. District (correspondence), 1963-1968; Series 3 (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - NVTC - Virginia Metropolitan Areas Transportation Study Commission, 1968; Series 3 (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - WMATA legislation [Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority], 1964; Series 3 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Legislation and reports NCTA 1960 and Joint Commission Washington Metro Area Problems, 1959-1960; Series 3 (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Joint Committee on Washington Metropolitan Area Problems, 1958; Series 3 (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Tri-State Commission - labor, 1963-1964; Series 3 (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Tri-State Commission - management companies, 1961-1965; Series 3 (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Tri-State Commission -physical facilities committee, 1966; Series 3 (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - Tri-State Proprietary Compact (plan of financing), 1963-1964; Series 3 (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - Tri-State Commission - press releases, 1965; Series 3 (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Tri-State Commission - proprietary Compact (federal negotiator), 1963; Series 3 (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - Tri-State Commission - proprietary compact (legal), 1964; Series 3 (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Tri-State Commission (proprietary comm.), 1962-1963; Series 3 (Box 100, Folder 8)
  - Tri-State Commission transportation planning board correspondence, 1965; Series 3 (Box 100, Folder 9)
  - Tri-State Commission Virginia transportation district (law), 1964-1965; Series 3 (Box 100, Folder 10)
  - Tri-State Commission Virginia transportation district (work papers), 1963-1964; Series 3 (Box 100, Folder 11)
  - Tri-State Commission Virginia action on compact, 1966; Series 3 (Box 100, Folder 12)
  - Tri-State Consent Legislation cooperative arrangements between NCTA and Authority, 1966-1967; Series 3 (Box 100, Folder 13)
  - Tri-State Consent Legislation law, 1966; Series 3 (Box 100, Folder 14)
  - Tri-State joint steering committee, 1964-1965; Series 3 (Box 100, Folder 15)
  - Tri-State liaison finance committee, 1966; Series 3 (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Tri-State Proprietary Compact 1965 NCTA legislation, 1965-1967; Series 3 (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - Tri-State - Washington Suburban Transit District - law (commission), 1965-1968; Series 3 (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Joint Transportation Commission meeting, 1964 May 22; Series 3 (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Comments by joint transportation commission on the report of the NCTA, undated; Series 3 (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - National Capital Transportation Act of 1960, 1959-1960; Series 3 (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - NCTA annual reports [Tri-State], 1966; Series 3 (Box 101, Folder 7)
  - National Capital Transportation Authority Compact [staff draft], undated; Series 3 (Box 101, Folder 8)
  - Metropolitan Area Transit study (data submitted by Public Service Commission Maryland [Capital Transit Co.], 1955; Series 3 (Box 101, Folder 9)
  - NCTC Highways [1/2], 1958-1960; Series 3 (Box 101, Folder 10)
  - NCTC Highways [2/2], 1958-1960; Series 3 (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Organization and procedure manuals, 1969-1975; Series 3 (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Regulation Compact background, 1953-1954; Series 3 (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Transit statements, testimony, compact, 1964, undated; Series 3 (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Commission executive of compact, 1955-1959; Series 3 (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - WMATA compact negotiations memos, undated; Series 3 (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - Financing plan [WMATA], 1966; Series 3 (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - WMATA National Capital Transportation Authority, 1964; Series 3 (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - WMATA organization, undated; Series 3 (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - Joint Transportation Commission / Tri-State Commission papers, 1964; Series 3 (Box 102, Folder 10)
  - Tri-State Commission budget during negotiations [1/2], 1964-1966; Series 3 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Tri-State Commission budget during negotiations [2/2], 1962; Series 3 (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Tri-State budget for Authority (JMA), 1966-1967; Series 3 (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Tri-State Commission - Proprietary Compact (minutes) [1/3], 1961-1964; Series 3 (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Tri-State Commission - Proprietary Compact (minutes) [2/3], 1962 March - July; Series 3 (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Tri-State Commission - Proprietary Compact (minutes) [3/3], 1962 March - August; Series 3 (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Tri-State Commission - Proprietary Compact (newspaper clippings), 1966; Series 3 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Tri-State Commission - Proprietary Compact (work papers), 1964; Series 3 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Tri-State Commission - Proprietary Compact (work papers), 1963-1964; Series 3 (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Tri-State Commission - source materials, 1959-1960; Series 3 (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - Transit Compact (metropolitan area, Washington, D.C.) legal-law, 1958; Series 3 (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - [Joint Transition Comission - Alper financials], 1964-1966; Series 3 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Tansit - Federal Corporation - NCPC (comments and legislation), 1959; Series 3 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Transit - Federal Corporation (N.C.P.C.), 1959-1960; Series 3 (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - Transit - Federal Corporation and Proprietary Compact, 1959-1960; Series 3 (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - Key Questions on Urban Transporation by Paul H. Gerhardt and John H. Nixon, 1962 September 10; Series 3 (Box 104, Folder 10)
  - Washington Gas Light Company Charter, 1848; 1953; Series 3 (Box 104, Folder 11)
  - Work papers [Transporation], 1958, undated; Series 3 (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Compact, 1964 September 1; Series 3 (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - WMATA report basic info [1/3], 1965-1966; Series 3 (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - WMATA report basic info [2/3], 1965-1966; Series 3 (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - WMATA report basic info [3/3], 1965-1966; Series 3 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Resident Engineer Diary Job No. 1A0171 book 1 of 2, 1979 February 8 - 1980 October 9; Series 3 (Box 106, Folder 1)
    The engineer is R. DeSouza. He used the initials NTP which may represent a location.
  - Resident Engineer Diary Job No. 1A0171 book 2 of 2, 1980 October 10 -1981 July 31; Series 3 (Box 106, Folder 2)
    The engineer is R. DeSouza. He used the initials NTP which may be a location.
  - Resident Engineer Diary Job No. 1A017A, 1983 June 2 - 1984 May 9; Series 3 (Box 106, Folder 3)
    Derwood Circle Extension. Two engineers: Engineer Gerald T. LeFevre from June 3, 1983 and then Craig L. Maxey January 1, 1984
  - Monthly progress photos 809.2 A-17dc [Derwood Circle Extension], 1983; Series 3 (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - Monthly progress photos 809.2 A-17dc [Derwood Circle Extension], 1983-1984; Series 3 (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - Derwood Circle Extension photos, 1979-1984; Series 3 (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - Derwood Circle Extension schematics, 1982; Series 3 (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - WMATA - Bus Trust #W 92.b, 1972; Series 3 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - WMATA - Bus Trust 92.c, 1973; Series 3 (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - WMATA - Capital Contributions Interim Agreement, 1976; Series 3 (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - WMATA - Commuter Service #110, 1969-1972; Series 3 (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - Memorandom of Understanding [WMATA] #W 89.b, 1972-1973; Series 3 (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - Second Interim Capital Contribution Agreement [WMATA] #W96A, 1979; Series 3 (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - Service Levels and Constraints [WMATA] #W89.c, 1973; Series 3 (Box 107, Folder 7)
  - WMATA - W.M.A.T.A. Compact, 1963; Series 3 (Box 107, Folder 8)
  - A Preliminary report on Labor Management Relations for the National Capital Transportation Agency, 1962; Series 3 (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - Capital Transit Company [1/2], 1954; Series 3 (Box 107, Folder 10)
  - Capital Transit Company [2/2], 1954; Series 3 (Box 107, Folder 11)
  - Capital Transit Company - purchase, 1960; Series 3 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Statement of Jerome M. Alper in support of H.J. Res 402, 1959; Series 3 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - History of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transportation Compact by Jerome M. Alpert, 1988 April; Series 3 (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - History of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transportation Compact Appendices by Jerome M. Alpert, 1988 April; Series 3 (Box 108, Folder 4)